And this new method is called DDIM.
这种新方法叫做DDIM。
So your goal is that you want more images, and you want them quickly.
你的目标是想要更多
的图片，并且快速得到它们。
But sampling so far has been slow because, one, there are many time steps involved,
但是到目前为止，采样速度
很慢，因为涉及到很多时间步骤，
And also each time step is dependent on the previous one.
而且每个时间步骤都依赖于前一个。
But thankfully, there are many new samplers here to address this problem, since this has been a long standing problem with diffusion models.
但幸运的是，有许多新的
采样器来解决这个问题，因为
这一直是扩散模型的一个长期问题。
It's that you can train them and they can create amazing, beautiful images that are both diverse and realistic,
你可以训练它们，它们可以创造出
既多样又逼真的惊人美丽的图像，
but it's so slow to get something out of them.
但从它们那里
得到结果的速度非常慢。
And one of these samplers that has been very popular is called DDIM, or Denoising Diffusion Implicit Models, which is just the name of the paper.
其中一种非常受欢迎的
采样器叫做DDIM，即去噪扩散
隐式模型，这只是论文的名字。
And this paper was written by Jiaming Song, Chenlin Meng, and my PhD co-advisor, Stefano Ermon.
这篇论文是由Jiaming Song、
Chenlin Meng和我的博士联合
导师Stefano Ermon共同完成的。
DDIM is faster because it's able to skip time steps.
DDIM之所以更快，
是因为它能跳过时间步长。
So instead of going from time step 500 to 499 to 498, it's able to skip all these time steps.
所以它不是从500步
到499步再到498步，而是
能跳过所有这些步骤。
And it's able to skip quite a bit, because it breaks the Markov assumption.
它能跳过很多步骤，
因为它打破了马尔可夫假设。
Markov chains are only used for probabilistic processes.
马尔可夫链只用于概率过程。
But DDIM actually removes all the randomness from this sampling process, and is therefore deterministic.
但DDIM实际上从这个
采样过程中去除了所有的
随机性，因此是确定性的。
And what it does, essentially, is it predicts a rough sketch of the final output.
它所做的，本质上就是
预测最终输出的粗略草图。
And then it refines it with the denoising process.
然后用去噪过程对其进行细化。
So let's compare DDPM here on the left, which is what we've been doing so far, and DDIM here on the right.
那么让我们比较一下左边
的DDPM，这是我们迄今为止
一直在做的，和右边的DDIM。
Yes, it is much faster with DDIM.
是的，使用DDIM速度快很多。
You immediately see a buck there after time step 19.
在时间步19之后，你
立即就能看到一个有形的结果。
And we're still going for DDPM.
我们还在继续使用DDPM。
We're still going.
我们还在继续。
And this goes all the way up to 500 with DDPM, as you know.
而且这一直可以
用DDPM达到500。
Great, so here's the lab.
好的，这里是实验课。
A lot of the setup will look the same.
很多设置看起来都一样。
So I'm just going to run this cell here, set up the unit again, our hyperparameters.
我只是在这里运行这个单元格，
重新设置单位，我们的超参数。
Here's the DDPM noise schedule.
这是DDPM噪声计划。
We'll use it to compare it to DDIM later.
稍后我们会用
它来和DDIM进行比较。
Now I'm instantiating the model.
现在我正在实例化模型。
So here's the function for DDIM.
这是DDIM的功能。
You can look at the paper for the details, but this implements that with its scaling factors.
可以查看论文了解细节，
但这里实现了相应的缩放因子。
So what's cool is that we can actually just load up the trained model and use either DDIM or DDPM.
很酷的是，我们可以
直接加载训练好的模型，
使用DDIM或DDPM。
It doesn't matter.
这都没关系。
This is just a sampling process after training.
这只是训练后的采样过程。
And the only thing to call out is that there is a step size involved.
需要指出的是，这里涉及到一个步长。
We're not going through every single time step.
我们没有逐个
时间步骤地进行。
We're actually skipping steps here.
实际上我们在
这里跳过了一些步骤。
And here is where n is 20.
这里的n是20。
So this is 500 over 20.
所以这是500除以20。
We'll run that here.
我们将在这里运行。
And then we can sample.
然后我们可以进行采样。
That was much, much faster.
这速度快了很多。
I could barely even see that there.
我几乎看不到那里。
All right.
好了！
So here's what that looks like.
这就是它的样子。
And it's very fast that it's able to instantly turn into these sprites.
它能够瞬间变成这些
游戏角色，速度非常快。
Now with this faster sampling method, you don't always get the same level of quality as if you were to run DDPM.
现在用这种更快的
采样方法，你并不总能
得到和使用DDPM一样的质量。
These actually do look quite good.
但这些实际上看起来相当不错。
Empirically, people have found that with a model trained on these 500 steps, for example,
实际上，人们发现，用在
这500步上训练的模型，例如，
But for any number under 500 steps, DDIM will do much better.
但对于任何小于500步
的数字，DDIM的表现会好得多。
And so now here's the same, but with a context model.
现在这里是相同的，
但带有上下文模型。
So you can load in that context.
所以你可以加载那个上下文。
Great.
太棒了！
So these are just random contexts here.
这些只是随机的上下文。
But you can set them yourselves as well.
但你们也可以自己设置。
And this is what they look like.
它们是这样的。
So now your question is probably, how does the speed compare?
那么现在你们可能
会问速度如何对比？
And we can compare it using  timeit  in this notebook.
然后我们可以在这个
Notebook中使用 timeit 进行比较。
So we're going to compare DDIM with DDPM.
我们将比较DDIM和DDPM。
All right.
好了
Look at that speed up.
看看这个速度提升。
So try running these in your own notebook and see what you get.
试着在你们自己的Notebook
中运行这些，看看结果如何。